Brená Bishop

Cleveland, OH | 330.998.1907 | bishop.brena@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/brenabishop| https://github.com/brenabishop/Portfolio.git

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Solution focused professional with experience in software design, testing, and application development. Comfortable with quickly learning new technologies, problem solving, and meeting deliverables individually and in a group setting. Passionate about merging the intricacies of developing applications and balancing business needs to deliver top-notch solutions.

TECHNICAL INVENTORY

Java • Spring • Hibernate • JPA • JavaScript • MVC • HTML • CSS • Flexbox • Grid • TDD • Agile (Scrum) • Object Oriented Programming (OOP) • AJAX • JSON • Restful APIs • Responsive Design / Mobile • Structured Query Language (SQL) • Relational Databases • Source Control / Git

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE

GitHub Address

We Can Code IT, Cleveland, OH **Software Development Student,** 2021

https://github.com/brenabishop

Planned, designed, and developed professionally programmed applications in collaborative team-based and independent settings, demonstrating the proficiency to earn Software Development Certificate.

Virtual Pet: Tamagotchi style console application

Java, IntelliJ, Github, GitBash, TDD, OOP, Pair Programming

Portfolio: Custom built website to showcase talents HTML, CSS, Flexbox, CSS Grid, Javascript

Fortune Teller: Console application to predict the future based on user input

Java, IntelliJ, Github, GitBash

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (WORK HISTORY)

Progressive

Multiproduct Blended Agent Sr., February 2020 - Present, Cleveland, OH

- Effectively manage and multiple CRMs to deliver a premier customer experience and increase company productivity
- Increased customer retention by sharing insurance expertise and using strategic sales methods to deliver optimal solutions
- Educated customers on current policy status as well as opportunities in order to help Progressive move towards becoming the #1 destination insurer.

Progressive

Multiproduct Agent., April 2018 - February 2020, Cleveland, OH

- Developed strategy to achieve top sales goals and increase company profit.
- Collected data and analyzed client need in order to present best possible solutions
- Boosted team morale by creating a committee to recognize achievements.
- Educated team members and increased team productivity by assessing department needs and leading training sessions.

Experient

Senior Housing Coordinator, July 2015 -- April 2018, Twinsburg, OH

- Improved onboarding process by facilitating think tanks and redefining role duties and training methods
- Advised a 6 person team to help bridge communication gaps between interoffice departments and successfully streamlined the development process.
- Minimized inefficiency in customer facing CRM by serving on a team to communicate with the programmers throughout the CRM design life cycle

Experient

Concession Coordinator, July 2013 - July 2015, Twinsburg, OH

- Maintain a consultative relationship between multiple clients ensuring a clean line of communication
- Implement unique processes based on event needs to lead to an increase in revenue
- Developed and implemented an improved process to efficiently manage the life cycle of accounts and minimize error

EDUCATION & TRAINING

We Can Code IT

Certificate of Software Development, 2021

Franklin University

Computer Science, In Progress

Relevant Coursework: Human/Computer Analysis, PHP, Java, Data Analytics, System Design & Analysis

VOLUNTEER WORK (Optional)

Boys & Girls Club

ROLE: Created and co-lead Tech Club for 6 - 18 years olds. Taught the fundamentals of coding, team-driven development, and built real world applications.